A Guide to the Edward Lawrie Tatum papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA133
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Film reels, 10; moving image
  - Tatum "Biochemistry of heredity", 1960 May 25; moving image, 16 mm sound on film kinescope. (Reel 1)
    RAC is unable to provide access to the original item, due to the specialized equipment necessary to facilitate playback. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
  - Kinescope reproduction of 1966 May television program for Merck building dedication, moving image (Reel 2)
    Aired on Sept 10, 1966 on NBC Research Projects "The future of medicine." Tatum "Molecular biology, nucleic acids and the future of medicine".
    [See: Merck, Sharp and Dohme file in Box 20 for Tatum address] [IN RAC FILM VAULT].
- Scientific photographs, 11; 6 items
  Some used in publications. Some identified and some in duplicate. Includes 1947 June LIFE photographs. Also includes group photographs with some identification.
  - Scientific photographs (Package a)
- U.S. Dept of State citation to E.L. Tatum for Public Service at International Science Exhibition, Brussels, 12
  - U.S. Dept of State citation to E.L. Tatum for Public Service at International Science Exhibition, Brussels, 1958 October (Package b)
- Collected Reprints
  - Collected reprints, 2 bound volumes
    - 1944-1962 (Volume 1)
    - 1963-1976 (Volume 1b)
  - Sloan-Kettering Symposium on macromolecules and cancer, New York City, 1965 October 18-20; 1 bound volume (Volume 3)
    Published in CANCER RESEARCH 26 (1966) 1955-2081. Tatum chairs session on genetics and macromolecules and gives "Introductory remarks". CANCER RESEARCH 26 (1966) 1958. [Not listed in Tatum bibliography] [Editor's note: In June 1980 Joshua Lederberg deposited this bound volume with RU Archives].
  - Collected reprints, 8 bound volumes
    Additional bound volumes of E.L. Tatum. Collected Reprints.
    [Bound volume 1a of collected reprints begins with 1944; the bibliography with 1932. The early reprints lacking].
    Immediate Source of Acquisition note
    RU Archives received May 1985.
    - 1932-1942 (Volume 2a)
    - 1943-1947 (Volume 2b)
    - 1949-1956 (Volume 2c)
    - 1956-1964 (Volume 2)
    - 1964-1968 (Volume 2e)
    - 1957-1962 (Volume 3a)
    - 1963-1965 (Volume 3b)
    - 1966-1973 (Volume 3c)